[MÖGE] It seems
the Great Kha'an was poisoned.
But still,
if it really wasn't you,
then that would mean
-it was Töregene.
-[gasps]
[KAM] The guardian spirits
have spoken,
and they tell us
that saving the patient
will require a sacrifice
in his stead.
One of you must drink
every last drop of this water.
Well then, looks like I'm up.
♪
[sighs]
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[Ögedei groans]
I'm in pain.
And I can't move.
-[birds squawking]
-[ÖGEDEI] I must be...
deep within the lower world.
The immortal realm...
where all the spirits
are said to dwell.
[dog barks]
Not even the kams themselves
would dare venture
so deep in search of a soul.
Is it now my fate to be held
captive here for eternity?
[TOLUI] Brother!
[Ögedei gasps]
[footsteps]
[TOLUI] So, this is where
you were, Ögedei.
[ÖGEDEI] Tolui?
Why are you here?
[Tolui grunts]
I can't tell you how long
I have searched.
After scouring
the upper and lower worlds,
it seems I've finally found you.
Come. Let's return.
Tolui, I'm afraid
that will not be possible.
[TOLUI] Uh?
[ÖGEDEI] If a single soul were
to go missing from this tent,
the spirits would
surely take notice.
In anger, they could wreak havoc
upon the surface.
[animals whine]
Then you must allow me
to switch places with you.
[ÖGEDEI] Huh?
Tolui, please don't.
Come now, all that
I've ever known is war.
We've already vanquished
our longtime foes, the Jin.
[laughs]
♪
Hmm.
[Ögedei gasps]
♪
[TOLUI] You're the one
who'll forge the era
to come with your cleverness.
[ÖGEDEI] No! Tolui!
Farewell, brother.
[ÖGEDEI] Tolui!
When you're back, I would like
for you to be careful.
And in my stead,
please watch over
Sorghaghtani for me!
♪
[Ögedei gasps]
[breathes heavily]
Great Kha'an.
[chuckles]
You've awakened.
Boraqchin? [grunts]
Where's Tolui?
Where is brother right now?
[Boraqchin exhales]
[Ögedei gasps]
[footsteps receding]
Everyone,
the Great Kha'an has come to.
[cries]
Tolui.
[bleating]
Uh? [gasps]
Sir Qadaq's tent is gone.
How can this be?
I needed to speak with him.
Surely he knew what happened
to Lady Töregene.
-[clink]
-Huh?
This is...
[Shira shouts] Fatima!
-[pants]
-[SITARA] Shira?
Prince Tolui has...
[breathes shakily]
[Sitara breathes uneasily]
What?
[SHIRA]
It happened after the exorcism.
[gasps]
[neighs]
[SHIRA] On his way back home
with the others,
Prince Tolui suddenly had a fit.
♪
[Tolui grunting]
[Sorghaghtani gasps]
[SHIRA] He managed to return
to Princess Sorghaghtani's side.
-But soon after, perished.
-[Sorghaghtani cries]
♪
[Shira sighs] It seems...
he really did choose
to sacrifice himself.
[SITARA] That can't be.
The very thought is absurd.
[Shira exhales]
Which would mean he was...
[Sitara gasps]
Assassinated?
Hold on. With everything that's
happened since yesterday,
I feel so confused.
Fatima, perhaps you shouldn't
go back to the House of Tolui.
-[gasps]
-The Princess sent you
to try and prevent
the very worst from occurring.
And yet, that is precisely
what happened.
So, she'll think
you've betrayed her trust.
[Sitara gasps softly]
Besides, now
that Prince Tolui isn't around,
his house won't last long.
[Sitara gasps]
[SHIRA] From now on,
the Great Kha'an
may have all the power.
Should that be the case,
I would love to serve
the House of Ögedei.
[gasps]
Say, Fatima...
Do you think you could
put in a good word for me?
Hey! Uh, you listening?
[SITARA (ADULT)]
Tolui sacrificed his life
so the Great Kha'an could live.
While that may very well
be the truth,
it could just as easily not be.
But one thing is certain,
following the death
of Prince Tolui,
the power imbalance
that once prevailed
within the empire...
was about to undergo
an immeasurable shift.
I now present
the jarghuchi, Shigi Qutuqu,
who'll be announcing
the spoils of war.
Here are the men we brought back
from the capital of Jin.
-Scholars...
-Yes.
...physicians, engineers.
They're sure to contribute
to our nation's development.
So this is the gift
you mentioned?
Did you call for me?
I spoke to the jarghuchi.
He told me you went
against the law
by arguing for more land
and subjects for your son.
[Kirgistani yelps]
[KIRGISTANI] My son made
valuable contributions
to the Jin expedition!
You do realize
what he accomplished,
-don't you?
-Mother!
[Kirgistani screaming]
-Pardon us. Pay her no mind.
-[KIRGISTANI] Godan!
[GODAN] Mother, please!
Try and calm down, all right?
Wait! Ow! Let go! That hurts!
[screams]
[laughs nervously]
Well, you see, uh...
That wish of yours
may be granted soon enough.
[KIRGISTANI] Uh...
Huh?
[Boraqchin chuckles]
[Sitara gasps]
-[grunts] Right there.
-Huh?
-[exclaims]
-[chuckles]
[Sitara sighs]
[BORAQCHIN] Fatima.
[Sitara gasps]
It's the Empress.
What brings you here?
[BORAQCHIN]
Your selfless efforts
have made the Great Kha'an's
recovery possible.
And to show my gratitude...
I want you to have this.
[SITARA] What?
"Elements?"
[BORAQCHIN]
I mentioned to Sorghaghtani
that you had
long been seeking this book,
and she gladly agreed
to part with it.
[SITARA]
That I had been seeking it...
[gasps] How did you know?
[Boraqchin chuckles]
[SITARA]
Did Lady Töregene tell you?
-Fatima.
-Uh?
You need to forget
about that woman now.
[Sitara gasps]
[BORAQCHIN]
I'll have her tent dismantled
by the end of today.
You can relocate
next to my tent immediately.
Empress Boraqchin.
[BORAQCHIN] Come.
There's something
I want to show you.
[SITARA] Uh?
[Sitara gasps]
♪
So, did Princess Sorghaghtani
relinquish all these books
to you?
Indeed. Rather graciously.
Uh, yes, but she said...
And I wish to learn more.
About the lands
within reach of Mongol hooves,
and the ones even farther.
[BORAQCHIN]
What happened to Tolui
was unquestionably tragic.
That said...
I believe it was a portent
from the heavens.
[Sitara gasps]
For, you see, the Great Kha'an
has the wisdom
to lead our empire
into a new age.
Yet, Tolui would have proved
quite meddlesome
in bringing
all this to fruition.
You told me as much yourself.
You were afraid
of the House of Tolui
dominating in both might
and intelligence.
[Sitara gasps]
But now,
I have the chance
to fix that imbalance.
Fatima, it won't be might
that commands
this empire's future.
It will be wisdom.
Don't you wish to harness
your own wisdom
to its fullest extent?
Could you imagine anything
more enjoyable?
[Sitara exclaims]
[wind blows]
[gasps]
♪
[SITARA] Had I stayed in Tus,
I would never have beheld
a sight so majestic.
That's why I'm leaving here
on a journey,
to engage with wisdom,
and search for truth.
♪
[SITARA] Master Muhammad...
I felt so frustrated
watching you leave us that day.
I was filled with envy.
You were free
to journey anywhere,
and follow your heart.
♪
I've already learned
and experienced
far more than you ever did
in the brief time
that you were alive.
Maybe the moment's
finally come...
for me to move on
with the rest of my life.
[wind blows]
-[loud clanging]
-[gasps]
[clanging]
[SOLDIER 1] Hold on.
What was that?
[SOLDIER 2]
Uh, hey, you all right?
[SOLDIER 3] I'm sorry.
This pillar just toppled over.
[Sitara gasps]
I thought surely
lightning had struck out here.
[Sitara gasps]
[Muhammad laughs]
Everyone down there
was so afraid.
♪
As of now,
you have no idea where you are,
what's really happening,
or what is going
to become of you.
Your life's full of unknowns.
[SITARA] How could I have
possibly imagined
I was cleverer
than Master Muhammad?
Where is my true place
in this world?
Euclid's Elements.
The book my mistress
tried to protect.
The book that would ultimately
be the cause
of her tragic death.
The man who took
my mistress's life is no more.
My single purpose in life
was to somehow
retrieve that book
and take it back as her slave.
♪
Mistress Fatima, I've succeeded
in what I set out to do.
A slave?
[gasps]
Empress Boraqchin...
Were you told
of my particular interest
in this book,
and why I sought it out?
[BORAQCHIN] Uh?
I believe it's a treatise
on geometry, is it not?
I was told you had an interest
in the subject for a long time.
And that you take after
your father,
who was a known scholar,
wasn't he?
[Sitara gasps]
[chuckles]
Yes, it's just as you said.
♪
[SITARA]
Now I'm sure of one thing.
Empress Boraqchin definitely
heard about this book
from Lady Töregene.
I can't guess
what might have transpired,
but what I can say is...
My name is Sitara. I am a slave.
That's why
I chose to hide my past,
and kept it a secret
from everyone I could.
Please keep it a secret, too.
[SITARA] Lady Töregene...
never once divulged
the secrets we shared.
Nor the anger we bear.
♪
[SHIRA] You worked hard today.
[horse snorts]
[sighs]
[whistling]
[continues whistling]
-[SITARA] Shira.
-[SHIRA] Huh?
Fatima?
I thought I told you
-not to come back here.
-I know.
But I could use your help.
Just answer my question,
and I'll introduce you
to the Great Kha'an
or the Great Khatun.
Very well, ask me anything.
Before, you told me
the House of Tolui
wouldn't last too long.
Why's that?
Think about it.
With Prince Tolui gone,
Princess Sorghaghtani
and the others
probably won't be able to
hold onto their influence now.
In fact, a little earlier...
[HULEGU] But Mother, they took
so many of your books,
and you're not saying anything?
And that book, Elements,
if I'm not mistaken,
didn't Father bring it
all the way from Persia for you?
[SORGHAGHTANI] It's fine.
At this point,
I've no further need for it.
The Great Khatun can take
anything she wants.
Ugh. I have no interest
in following somebody
who's lost all hope.
-[Sitara exhales]
-[gasps]
[SITARA] It was...
It was her. [cries]
I've been at the mercy
of Empress Boraqchin all along.
I hate this.
I believed I was smarter
than everyone around me,
and challenged her
completely unaware.
[Shira gasps softly]
[Sitara cries]
But right now isn't the time
to dwell on this.
Shira, I beg you.
Please help me.
There is someone
I need to save now. Chuu!
[SHIRA] Uh, wait!
Hold on.
Don't just leave me behind.
[grunts, pants]
Chuu!
♪
-[SITARA] Sir Qadaq...
-Uh?
Fatima, you found me.
Here. This is your
branding iron, am I right?
[Qadaq gasps]
-[breathes uneasily]
-[SITARA] Uh?
[SITARA] Sir Qadaq...
Where is Lady Töregene?
Please tell me she's safe!
Let me assure you,
I'm doing all I can
to make sure she's safe.
On my master's orders, that is.
-Master?
-Isn't that Lady Töregene?
I've told you countless times,
she's not!
[sighs]
[grunts]
It's a rather long story.
Come with me.
[QADAQ]
Prince Güyük, I'm coming in.
[Sitara gasps]
There's no one here.
[QADAQ]
Prince Güyük, it's me, Qadaq.
[Güyük yelps]
[whimpers]
Qadaq?
[BOTH] Huh?
Oh, it's just you?
I thought a stranger was...
[yelps]
[SITARA] Uh, an honor to--
-[screaming]
-[all yelp]
-[Qadaq sighs]
-[whimpers]
[GÜYÜK] Qadaq! Qadaq!
Who is she? Send her away!
[QADAQ] Well,
the prince's temperament
can be quite unpredictable.
Today is not your day. Get out.
[BOTH] Huh?
Come on, you aren't
really serious, are you?
Qadaq,
what is the meaning of this?
-It's like I said--
-[GÜYÜK] Qadaq!
[Qadaq groans]
I beg of you!
I don't know who that man is,
but Lady Töregene
needs his help.
[QADAQ] Well, this is
her firstborn son!
[Güyük whimpering]
[Qadaq sighs]
The Great Kha'an
and Lady Töregene
are his parents.
[Sitara gasps]
What?
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[SITARA (ADULT)] Next time,
"An Ungraceful Stone."